Holy shit !
You scared me to death , man !
There 's nothing down there .
I think we 're leaving empty-handed .
This isn 't about how many fish we catch .
It 's about having a good time .
Don 't you just want to paddle to Miami sometimes ?
What for ?
There , I have to work .
Here , I 'm a harvester like the Tainos .
It 's just a matter of sitting and waiting .
Something will come up .
Besides , I 'm a survivor .
I survived Mariel , I survived Angola , I survived the Special Period ,
and that thing that came later .
Just give me a chance , and I 'll sort it out .
Look , my luck is getting better . What did I tell you , Lazaro ?
This is paradise , and nothing will change that .
Is he dead ?
This stays between us , okay ?
Doesn 't El Neni owe you money ?
What a bastard ! Here .
Neni !
- You 're a sucker ! - Neni !
My dad is better than you .
Who 's your dad ?
Pick that up . Come on !
And count the chips .
Your dad is a sodomite .
- What 's a sodomite ? - A chemical substance .
- Can I help you , Yiya ? - Thank you , Sonny .
Juanito , what would I do without you ?
With Rogelio who hasn 't stood up for years !
- Whoops ! 'Again !
I 'm going to lift you up , Yiya . Careful .
- Don 't take advantage ! - I 'll try not to .
That 's it .
Now the other knee .
Did you just touch my bum ?
I couldn 't help myself .
Hey ! What 's up , Sara ?
Listen , the other day , you left the window open .
What a sublime show .
When he told me , I had to touch myself .
By the way , you look good in those red shoes .
Sara , what if you and I - - ?
Please ! You 'd have to be the last man on Earth .
Those chicks are crazy about me , man .
How do these chicks know when they 're done ?
I 'll tell you how .
I jerk off , I come , and that 's it .
But their hands get tired , and their tongues get numb .
What does Sara do , man ?
She 's a blogger .
Oh ...
One of those people who write nonsense on the Internet .
JUAN OF THE DEAD
You 're getting your family in trouble , and then you 'll feel bad .
Show me that watch , shit !
Hey , you ! What are you looking at ? Beat him up and shake him down .
- There 's a meeting today , right ? - I 've already told them .
Look , you have to get your kid out of this .
He should study something . Not be a crook .
That 's it , California . That 's my son .
- Give it to her . - Hey !
He can do much better , man . You can 't let him follow our footsteps .
He likes it , Juan . What the hell can I do ?
What the hell do I know ?
You should 've paid more attention to him .
Play ball with him more often . I don 't know .
At least he 's here with me , in Cuba .
Wouldn 't you like to have been raised better ?
I don 't complain about ourselves ,
but there are different ways to move forward in life .
What 's up , Mommy-in-Law ? Did you miss me ?
Thank God it 's been a long time I haven 't been your mother-in-law .
Why did you come ? Camila isn 't here .
Grandma , who is it ?
- Come in . - Thank you .
I 'm in the shower . I 'll be right there .
I was surprised you didn 't come before .
I thought you were in prison .
- Why would I be in prison ? - Because nature is wise .
Has it been a while since you arrived ?
Too long for you not to have known already .
When you do that , you steal my heart .
The last time I saw you , you stole many things from me .
- You 're just like your mother . - Thank goodness I came out like her .
Cami , I swear , I 've changed .
No , Juan , you 're like this country .
Many things happen to you , but you never change .
By the way , I 'm going to Miami .
Things aren 't easy in Spain , and mom has decided to start from scratch .
Damn it , Camila , you can 't do this to me .
I can 't live without you .
You 've been doing pretty good all this time , so get used to it .
I 'm being honest .
Give me a chance .
Leave .
Let 's go for a fifth time .
Damn ! My husband !
The boy doesn 't want to play ball with me .
Where were you , man ?
Holy shit , that 's a hot brunette . Great move .
Hasten to battle , men of Bayamo
The motherland looks proudly to you
Do not fear a glorious death
Because to die for the motherland is to live ...
- Why do we always meet here ? - It 's a tradition .
- Good evening . - Good evening .
Mario isn 't feeling well today , so he asked me to talk with you .
Okay , let 's get started .
Yudmila says we need more whiskey , so get it from Loco .
Darling , don 't you know Loco died ?
With your habit of fishing in that little raft of yours ,
you 're eating more shit every day .
Like Alice ... " in the Wonderland . " Careful !
Eight radios have been stolen this week from parked cars . Here !
We need to pay attention to any irregularity .
The public health inspectors were also here
to warn us about a possible epidemic .
Apparently , there 's some new virus or something .
What ? One has to make a living .
Listen , you don 't shit where you eat .
Girlie , if I get caught because of you ...
This asshole 's asking for it .
Look , tell your boyfriend that no one talks to La China like that
because if I lose my temper , I 'll let Primo loose .
And he didn 't eat yesterday .
There 's chocolate here for the whole winter .
I dare you ! They call me the Normandy Butcher .
Why 's that ?
Because I minced steaks at the Normandy Restaurant .
All right , Gentlemen , we didn 't come here to see who 's got a bigger one .
We came to organize ourselves .
We need all these people to forget about the radio thing .
Mario ? What 's wrong , darling ?
Oh , Mommy !
Oh , shit !
- They bit Emilio ! - He 's a pussy ! Such a pussy !
Check this out ...
But what the hell is this ?
Oh ! He can 't stand the sight of blood .
- Let 's move it . This is getting ugly . - We won 't help those people ?
No , no , no . Fuck them .
They must have forgotten all the robbery stuff .
Hey !
Hey , aren 't you going to help me with this giant ?
Hey , Papa Smurf ! Fuck you !
Official report .
There have been some problems with social discipline
in different areas of the capital .
The police investigate isolated riots
apparently caused by some dissident groups paid by the U .. government .
Dissidents ...
Don 't fuck with me . Mario isn 't a dissident .
I 've never seen a bigger fat pussy squealer in my life .
That 's true .
What I don 't like is all this quiet everywhere .
It 's not good for business .
There aren 't even tourists .
This is all crumbling .
I want to leave this place and travel around the world .
If anyone asks where I 'm from , I 'll say I 'm from Cuba .
If they ask me what Cuba is ,
I 'll say it 's a small socialist island in the Caribbean .
If they ask me what socialism is ,
I 'll say it 's a system established by Fidel Castro 50 years ago .
If they ask me who Fidel Castro is , I 'll stay there forever !
That 's my boy . Just so you know !
Son , your words have moved me deeply .
Holy shit , California , keep it up .
You 'll do better than your father .
Wait here for me for a moment .
It seems something 's up with that crazy old bastard .
What happened , Yiya ?
Juanito , I think my old man died on me !
He looks the same as always .
I took him to the polyclinic yesterday to get an injection .
He 'd been complaining all day ,
but since he always complains , I ignored him !
I called the family doctor ,
but he told me he 'd come when he had a chance .
He had lots of patients
because there 's some kind of flu or something going on .
I won 't lie to you , Yiya . I think you 're right .
He 's no longer with us .
Don 't do this that me ! Oh , my goodness ! Oh , my God !
No , calm down . Take it easy . I 'm not a doctor .
You should call an ambulance first .
I wanted to see you like this since I was a kid , you old fucker .
I have the number here !
No , don 't worry .
Looks like he was just sleeping soundly .
Old man , you scared me so bad !
Yiya , call an ambulance anyway . Just to be sure , okay ?
Oh , dear , what would I do without you ?
- When did Rogelio stop walking ? - 15 years ago . Why ?
A miracle !
No , no . I don 't believe it 's a miracle , Yiya .
A miracle , a miracle !
Call my house and tell them to come down .
Rogelio , what 's wrong with you ?
Yiya , call my house , please !
It 's Yiya , the neighbor from 8B .
Oh , sweetheart , not too bad . You know how it is at this age .
Yeah , I saw the boy the other day . So cute .
Yiya !
Juanito wants you to come down for a moment . It 's urgent !
I don 't know what 's wrong with him ! He 's never been violent !
This is because of the expired drugs they give away at the polyclinic !
Rogelio ! What have they done to you ? What happened to you ?
- Help me , damn it ! - You know me , Rogelio !
Take it easy on him . He 's very old .
- I 've got an idea . - Dad , the two of us can 't hold him !
Rogelio , look at me ! It 's me , Yiya !
- Step aside , Juan . - What are you going to do with that ?
- It worked yesterday . - Give it to me , man .
You are not going to harpoon the old man .
- Yes , I am - - - But it 's Rogelio , damn it !
He 's a crazy bastard !
I will never let you touch that harpoon again !
This is not a dissident .
Vampires ?
- I told you to get a stake ! - This scares them .
Go find a stake , damn it !
Juan , don 't shout at me because I get stuck .
This building is very weird , man , it 's very weird .
Hey , the garlic thing is not working .
Hold him tight .
Silver bullets ?
Do you have anything to shoot them with ?
Do you even have any silver ?
Maybe he 's possessed ?
Demon , leave this body in peace . Demon , leave this body in peace !
Demon , leave this body in peace !
- That 's not a prayer ! - Do you know any ?
Demon , damn the entrails ' blood of the mother who gave birth to you !
Fuck you , Demon ! Leave this body in peace , Demon !
Let him go , damn it !
Get out of there ! Get out , damned Demon !
Fuck you , Demon !
Son , these dissidents are well fed !
And what do we do now ?
- More careful with the old lady ! - What 's wrong ?
Boy , the old lady was nice .
The least we can do is to treat her with respect .
What 's that ?
Jump ! Jump !
Shit !
I 'll start working out tomorrow with the old guys at the park .
I 'm telling you , man , this neighborhood is really weird .
Stop breaking my balls ! I don 't know what 's going on .
This is the quietest place in the world .
Don 't look at me .
She was so hot .
Come on . The cops are coming .
Sara ?
This is bringing out the good neighbor in me .
Thank you , God !
Mari , I don 't know what happened .
She was feeling ill ... She was trying to bite me .
We fought . I don 't know ...
It was an accident .
I believe you .
Come with me if you want to live .
Let 's go !
This is what I can offer you .
Relax . Take a bath .
The revolutionary police force warns all citizens
about some incidents produced by antisocial people
in collusion with the empire .
The population has come out on the streets ...
- What does " collusion " mean ? - It means we 're gonna get fucked .
... To hold a protest in favor of our country .
It is through this media that we 're encouraging you
to participate in a demonstration tomorrow at 5 : 00 p.m.
in front of the anti-imperialist tribune
to protest recent aggressions by the United States government .
What 's going on ? Anything new ?
Nothing . There are no cars . The stores are closed .
Like in the Special Period .
Maybe this will bring those dissidents down a peg or two .
I very much doubt it .
It looks the same to me .
You think so ?
Take a good look .
What 's he doing ?
He was acting so mature last night .
California !
Shit !
Shit ! Can 't these people shut up when they see someone 's working ?
You 're a boy , man .
I 'm going to get rich with all this .
I don 't think it looks like anyone can get rich .
- What ? We have to be ready . - They 're not American , man .
I have the feeling that this requires a plan of some kind
which I don 't have right now .
Go wait for me at home . I have to do something .
Juan , Juan !
You have to climb ! I can 't lift you up on my own !
Can 't you see that I 'd die without you ?
Juan , don 't start with that , okay ?
- Did you see my grandmother ? - More or less ...
- How is she ? - She looks just the same .
They taught me that in Angola . It 's a long story .
Hey , California , I need a favor .
Take care of her .
- And you are ... ? - Camila .
California . Vladi California .
My daughter , Camila .
You have a daughter ?
She doesn 't look like you at all .
If you lay a finger on her ,
I 'll rip your balls off and stick them up your ass .
Be careful with this guy . He has herpes .
- And my deck chair ? - My dad took it .
Where to ?
Fuck !
Stop , asshole !
Keep going . You and I are going to start a new life ... together .
You shut up ! You can 't just fucking leave .
Don 't break my balls , Juan .
It 's impossible to live in this country , man .
Over there , you 'll have to work for a living .
- This situation will pass . - Yeah ?
But what if it goes on like this another 50 years ?
I have an idea . We 'll get rich with this .
You 're indispensable , man . I can 't do anything without you .
Don 't say that , man .
Sara , I ...
And how do we get out of here ?
Like we always do .
We just need a chance . That 's all we need .
The first thing we have to do is arm ourselves well .
We need to be careful .
From now on , we just go out for the bare essentials : rum .
- And food ? - Yes , well ... That too .
The dissidents are not very smart . That 's our advantage .
I think they look drugged ... like in " Scarf ace . "
The one with Muni or the one with Pacino ?
The one with Rocco Sifreddi .
We have to take advantage of the fact
that everyone 's very busy fighting or trying to escape
and they still don 't know what 's going on .
And what 's going on ?
Not a clue .
We 're facing a crisis , and there 's only one thing we can do .
- Help them ? - No .
Charge them .
30 a head .
50 if we clean the place up and get rid of the bodies .
Discounts for old people and children under 12 .
Foreigners and anyone with relatives abroad pay double .
I think we also need to find a catchy name for the business .
Juan ?
This is another long story .
- You told me you 'd change ! - And I have changed .
Juan of the Dead , we kill your loved ones .
How can we help you ?
What ? I am just trying it out to see how it sounds !
You 're going to charge people ?
Cami , we 're Cuban !
It 's what we do when things get tough !
If that 's what you want to do , do it to help , not for money !
Girl , you 're the one living abroad with your mother .
Because there 's nobody here worth staying for .
Juan , you know I didn 't mean that .
You 're right .
Tell me what I can do to show you I 've changed .
Well , most of you have already been in this kind of classes .
It 's like Preparation for Defense ,
only this time , the bad guys are not the Yankees ,
but a real enemy , and they 're here , among us .
As far as we know , there 's no stopping these people .
They want to eat .
Just like in the Special Period , but they don 't eat just cats .
Let 's see , what else can you tell me about them ?
If you cause them a severe brain trauma , you 'll destroy them .
Wow ...
- Okay , anything else ? - Some are fast and some are slow .
Right . Some are slow and others are fast .
Can anyone tell me why ?
What a pity . I was eager for someone to clarify that for me .
Behave yourself !
We 're gonna teach you amateur techniques to arm yourselves
and be able to survive without any problems .
Let 's take this , for example .
Ernestico !
I told you not to bring any students ' relatives .
Shit , Juan , it 's getting harder and harder to capture them .
These are from the neighborhood .
Sprinkle some water on the old lady .
And when she 's better , you charge her 30 pesos .
No freebies here for anyone . We 're already altruistic enough .
Okay , it doesn 't matter .
From now on , we 'll call the fast ones " hares " and the slow ones " turtles . "
In a combat situation , the hares are your primary targets ...
You should be proud . He 's doing this for you .
I 'll be proud when he does it for them or for himself .
You haven 't spent too much time together , have you ?
You eventually get used to it .
I remember that when the dollar was penalized ,
my dad had me carry them for him .
In case they arrested us . They would never arrest me .
Yeah ? Well , that 's nothing .
My mom told me he dressed me up in old clothes and dirtied my face
to take me to Old Havana - -
- To beg stuff of tourists ! - Yes !
And well , because all that crazy stuff Juan did ,
my mother decided we had to leave .
I used to have fun .
Your company would 've been nice .
- Juan told me about you . - Yes ? And what did he say ?
That I have what ?
Let 's go , Juan ! We have work to do .
Juan of the Dead , we kill your loved ones .
How can I help you ?
What do we do with these people ?
Can you handle the three in front ?
I can take care of them with just a shoe .
Let 's go ! This is self-defense .
Hey , look !
Come here .
Come here !
So you don 't get this wrong ,
I want to tell you that La China will not stay home
nursing the eighth wonder
while you line your pockets with money .
So , let 's go .
Don 't fuck with me . This guy can 't even stand the sight of blood .
70-30 the first few times .
Don 't be greedy , Mister . 50-50 .
No way , dear China .
Go back to your nest in Canton . It doesn 't work that way .
- 60-40 . - It worked . Come on .
360 !
Knee to the north !
Down !
- China ! - Get away , bitch ! Get away !
I don 't know what to do with this one .
He doesn 't bother me .
I give up ! I give up ! Please ! I 'm a teacher ! I don 't know where I am !
- Sorry , Brother . Come with me . - You 're just not normal .
So sorry , Brother .
What 's going on ? Where am I ? What did he do ?
Lazaro , don 't ! Damn it , Lazaro , don 't ! Lazaro !
Lazaro ! Lazaro !
Stop !
What ?
He owed me money .
Come on .
Hey ! Cut it outwith that bell ! Vladi cut it out , asshole !
- Skinny fucker ! - What 's wrong ? They 're slow !
What do you mean , " slow " ? Can 't you see they 're behind us ?
Hurry up , China ! Hurry ! Move it ! Move it !
A helicopter , Juan ! They 're coming to save us !
Keep your voices down because they 're upstairs .
And if we don 't make any noise , they won 't get upset .
So , Ma 'am , how many people are we talking about ?
- Well , I rent four rooms ... - Yes
but I only declare two .
- You know how things are . - And are the rooms full ?
I have four Spaniards .
That 's 60 CUCs . And if you want us to take care of - -
- But that 's not all . - No ?
The Spanish must not be on their own , you know ?
Don 't worry , but you will have to pay for every extra person .
- How shall we do it ? - Like always .
We go in and see what we can wipe out .
With ax in hand .
Fucking Spaniards !
- It could be worse . - Really ? How ?
Fuck your mother 's heart .
Everyone , everyone ...
Don 't touch my ass !
- We rocked . - And where is ... ?
The poor lady ! She seemed like a good woman .
What happened ?
Check the house because I 'm not leaving without my money .
Okay , Juan , take it easy . Come on .
Juan of the Dead We kill your loved ones .
Juan of the Dead , we kill your loved ones .
How can I help you ?
No , Ma 'am . This isn 't the hairdresser .
You know he faints easily .
Juan of the Dead , we kill your loved ones .
How can I help you ?
You mean the Paralympics champions ?
No , that 'll be expensive .
Iconoclasts !
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL BUILDERS OF THE FUTURE
It wasn 't me , damn it ! That wasn 't my fault .
Come on , man . Keep moving and don 't stop !
Hey , wait for me ! Don 't get mad at me , shit !
Juan of the Dead , we kill your loved ones .
How can I help you ?
A cow ? No , no , no , man , that 's a big mess .
No , no , no .
Help ! Help ! Help ! Help ! Help !
The old man ! Help him !
- And the old man ? - He died . We had to leave him behind .
Not necessarily in that order .
Juan of the Dead , we kill your loved ones .
How can I help you ?
Who ?
No , no , friend , that 's your own business .
It 's a nice view , isn 't it ?
Yeah .
It 's a shame that building blocks out the sunset .
The situation is under control again .
Shut up !
Vladi , what 's wrong with you ?
He told Camila that I have herpes .
That 's not a big deal , boy .
Let 's see , raise your hand if you don 't have herpes .
All this bitching and at the end of the day ,
the only thing that works is public transportation .
- Do you think it 's safe to get on ? - Was it ever safe ?
REVOLUTION OR DEATH
We 'd better walk .
Come on .
I don 't know why it is that every time one finds a way to survive - -
ta-daaah - - things get ugly
and as tough as the Russian steppes .
And why don 't you just leave , boy ?
Step aside !
Mother of God !
Nothing but dick when God created that guy !
Put your weapons down !
- Identify yourselves ! - We 're altruists .
Take your clothes off .
You could 've waited a minute .
What do you mean take our clothes off ?
Take your clothes off or we 'll open fire .
There 's no need to intimidate .
Come on , turn around . Let 's go .
Move ! To the truck !
Move !
Juan , if you cover that with a scarf , it becomes a boy scout .
China !
Come on , we 're going !
What 's the reason for this , friend ?
We have to pick up everyone in the streets .
There are just a few of us left - - half a dozen - -
and we 've decided to start from scratch .
We 're rescuing all survivors and supplying them with arms .
You will build the walls of our community .
Darling , you have such a beautiful voice .
What 's your name ?
- Gabriel . - I can 't believe it .
Gabriel , like the archangel !
I don 't know if you 've noticed ,
but even though they call me " La China , "
my hands were not made to build walls .
If you 're not with the community , you 're against the community .
Boy , it 's always the same thing in this country !
Look , this is part of the world heritage
and showing it for free is a waste .
You could at least let us put our clothes back on .
Don 't worry . You don 't need clothes where you 're going .
Sergeant , I think you 're doing your job very badly .
Really ?
The keys ! The keys ! Quickly !
The gun ! The gun ! The gun !
All right , let 's organize things .
Vladi , food . Lazaro , rum .
And you , Primo , find something to cut the handcuffs .
I 'm sick of being tied up to the little girl here .
Excuse me ? " Little girl " ?
You didn 't see the camping tent between my legs , did you ?
- Camila ! - Ow ...
Camila !
- Juan , don 't shout . - Camila !
- Juan , lower your voice ! - Camila !
- Juan , stop yelling , man . - Take it easy .
I 'm looking for my daughter . Camila !
- Look , listen to me . - Camila !
Camila !
It hurts here ... Take a look and see what I - -
Juan , look what I have to do to surprise you !
- Juan , I 'm not feeling well . - Me neither . What the hell ?
What 's that ?
What , Juan ?
Oh , man , a scratch . I must have hurt myself in the truck .
Are you sure ?
Juan , don 't make a fuss . Of course I am .
- Camila ! - Juan , don 't shout .
Camila !
Juan , don 't shout ! I 'm not feeling well .
Quickly , find something to cut his handcuffs ! He 's dying !
No offense , China .
Hurry up ! I don 't want to be next to him when he gets annoying !
China , I 'll give you a bigger share in the business ,
but please , don 't do this to me .
China ! China !
Do you know what 's going on ?
- She wants to kill me - She wants to kill me
- She wants to hit me - She wants to hit me
- She wants to make me sleep - She wants to make me sleep
- And I won 't let her - No , no , no
- She wants to kill me - She wants to kill me
- And I won 't let her - No , no no
- What 's going on ? - Come on up , come on up
- She wants to kill me - She wants to kill me
She wants to hit me
And what happened here ?
What the hell !
Hurry ! Find something to cut this !
Here !
No , no , no ! Don 't even think about it !
No , no , no ! Are you high or something ?
Vladi !
- What 's this for ? - For his hand .
Oh ! Okay .
Leave me alone , fucking China !
- Good idea . - Thanks !
Did you get what I asked you for ?
Listen , man , I got to the place and my mind went blank .
What is it that I had to do ?
Official release .
Once again , our people have proven that they 're invincible .
We have rejected another aggression from the United States .
To all citizens : You may continue with your daily routine .
Everything is back to normal .
ONE MONTH LATER
Are there many of them ?
Like the last few weeks . They 're all infected .
There 's no one normal left .
I bet I can smash the skinny one 's head .
Take this !
Fuck , Lazaro ! Can 't you distinguish the good ones from the bad ones ?
Girl , it 's always been difficult to do that in this country .
Here comes Vladi .
- Did he make it ? - Yes .
It looks like he found food .
Juan , your hot neighbor is a dissident , too .
Fuck ! I ' d forgotten about Lucia .
Juan , you have to see this !
Change of plans . Let 's get the fuck out of here !
Should we go to the mountains and start an uprising ?
You 're joking now ,
but that 's what we should 've done from the beginning .
Fuck , don 't look at me like that ! It 's the truth .
I won 't stay here waiting for things to get better
while Havana burns down .
Juan , we can 't fight them all .
Plan B , let 's look for a boat to leave .
To Miami ?
Anywhere .
To Miami if there 's no other choice .
Fuck , in the end , capitalism will take its toll on us .
Get ready ! Arm yourselves well ! We have to get out of here !
- Where is everybody ? - In their homes . Can 't you hear them ?
Will they stay there forever ?
It won 't be much different from what they did before .
If we 're going to do this , let 's do it with style .
Juan , step aside !
Should we just leave her ?
What better place for her to spend the rest of her life ?
Let 's go to that car !
Come on .
Don 't tell me you guys can 't drive !
Later , we 'll all have a very serious chat !
Juan , hurry up ! They 're already coming .
Hurry , Juan ! Hurry , Juan ! They 're getting closer !
What 's going on ?
- Juan ! - Hurry ! They 're getting closer !
Juan ! Juan they 're getting closer !
Please , hurry !
Fuck ! Leave me alone !
Fuck you !
Juan , hurry . Hurry , hurry ! Please !
God damn it , Juan !
NOW !
We fucked them ! Hell , yeah !
Dissidents , imperialists , slaves , faggots , pieces of shit !
Motherfucking Russians that brought these fucked-up Lada cars to Cuba !
Juan , please , forget about the car !
Primo , don 't even think about taking the blindfold off or you 'll faint .
What should we do now ?
What can we do ? Follow her !
Camila !
Plan C , there 's a shelter at the corner .
- A shelter ? - Yeah , man , a shelter !
Go underground and come out armed when the enemy attacks .
Up , Primo . This got good .
Vladi , you protect Snow White .
Hey , people , can you tell me what 's wrong ?
Calm down , Primo . Juan is taking us to a safe place .
Step aside , Juan . This is a man 's job .
See ? I opened it !
Juan !
Primo !
Juan , enough of your great plans !
We went from being an orchestra to a garage band !
We just need a chance . That 's all we - -
Please ! Don 't start with that now , okay ?
Camila , everything I did was intended to help you .
Look , when I first saw you in your mother 's arms ,
from that moment , you 've been the love of my life .
Sorry to interrupt this cute love scene .
Look that way .
No fucking way !
Get down !
Wow ...
What is he saying ?
I don 't know , but let 's get in the car .
He was a fucking pain in the ass !
- Vladi , did you get that ? - No , I only speak Italian .
Don 't look at me . You were the English teacher .
But that was in high school !
Well , that 's more than the rest of us know .
Didn 't they teach you English in Spain ?
Juan , I 'm really bad at languages .
- Juan , ask him what 's going on . - That 's all I can say in English .
Juan , our lives are at risk , so cooperate .
What are they ?
Possessed people ? Werewolves ? Vampires ?
Dissidents ? Lobsters ?
And ? What did he say ?
Something about Old Havana .
Yes , I understood that , too .
- Yeah . - Okay .
Okay . Then ask him how to stop them .
You asshole !
I didn 't mean to .
Juan , these friends of yours give me the creeps !
- So , what did he say ? - He had a plan .
Fuck ! Don 't look at me like that !
This cocksucker killed him before he told me what it was !
Juan , apologizing won 't bring him back .
Take it easy !
Let me sit and think about our next move .
- Kids , I - - - Lazaro
you 're disgusting !
Man , you sure know how to screw things up !
Boy , why don 't we take one of those cars and we arm it - - I don 't know - -
like a tank .
We add on some metal sheets ...
I mean , an amphibian .
And there must be enough food in this building to take with us .
Fuck , Brother , that sounds like something we can do .
Right ?
Juan , there 's something else .
Tell me , tell me . If you 're going to go on like this , shoot .
No , Brother , no .
Yes .
I don 't care if I die .
What I would hate is waking up next to you guys like this .
Lazaro , you can 't ask me to do that .
And why not ? I 'd hit you with the machete without mercy .
Really ?
Sure .
Well , okay , I 'll do it .
Is there anything you want to do before ?
I 'd like to see one last sunrise .
- How do you want me to do it ? - I don 't understand .
Should I smash your head with my paddle ,
drop you from the building , chop you with a machete ?
How do you want me to do it ?
On the head , with the paddle .
But , please , don 't hit my face .
I was in more than 25 brawls , but no one ever hit my face .
If when the sun comes up , you 're still not dead
should I kill you ?
Juan , you 're a real pain in the ass . Wait until I die , would you ?
Will you take care of my kid ?
As if he were mine .
Juan , there 's one thing I always wanted to tell you .
Tell me .
I love you .
I love you , too , Brother .
No , you don 't understand . I love you .
Come on , Lazaro ...
I hid this from you this whole time , but now , who cares ?
I love you . I really love you .
- Are you angry at me ? - No , not angry . Not at all .
Would you let me give you a blow job ?
Be careful , man !
Be careful or you won 't see the sunrise !
I 'm sure I won 't see it . So , who cares ?
Come on , just a taste .
Juan , you can 't refuse a dying man a favor .
Come on , don 't be mean .
Okay , go ahead ! Nobody will know anyway .
I fucking gotcha , Brother !
Man , you 're a huge faggot !
You shit-head !
You 're a real dirty bastard .
You 're just like those metro sexual men .
You 're a good friend , Juan . No doubt about that .
Don 't touch me . I 'm not totally convinced yet .
Free Havana
Fuck , dickhead , faggot ! You hit me hard !
But what happened ? Why aren 't you dead ?
What the fuck do I know , man ?
Are you a 100 percent sure they bit you ?
30 .
Come on , let 's go . We have to make sure the kids are okay .
Get up . Move .
We have a lot of things to search for .
I have a plan .
Of all the crazy ideas you ever had , I think this is the worst one .
I know .
Do you think the same thing is going on outside ?
I don 't know .
Do you think mom is fine ?
We 'll get out of this , right ?
Are you sure about this , Juan ?
In the end , this is a fucking island and the only way out is by sea .
How are you feeling ?
Just like when I came into the world . Full of shit and piss .
Let 's see what we 're made of .
Iconoclasts ! Faggots !
Anarchic dissidents !
- Will it be enough with these guys ? - I hope so .
Help ! Help !
Help !
- Motherfucker ! - Help !
- You go on , and I 'll reach you later . - You sure ?
Are you okay ? Did they bite you ?
My dad tried to bite me , but I escaped .
Okay , close your eyes .
Sodomite !
Cross your fingers .
Damn it , Juan !
Get in , Juan .
Juan ! Juan , you can 't do this !
Actually , I should 've done it from the beginning .
Maybe things wouldn 't have turned out so bad .
Juan , don 't be such a jerk . Get in the car . Come on !
I 'm a survivor .
I survived Mariel , I survived Angola , I survived the Special Period ,
and this thing that came afterward .
And I will survive this .
Maybe people will see me and join me to help .
I 'm fine here . I like it here .
Over there , you have your mother .
She 'll take care of you .
Will you give your mom a kiss for me ?
Dad , please ...
It 's the first time you call me that .
Take care of her , okay ?
Shit , you make a good couple .
If you touch her , I 'll cut your dick off !
And now , get the hell out of here or I 'll start crying .
I 'll be all right .
I just need a chance .
I am Juan .
UNTIL VICTORY ALWAYS